Andy Josué Ruiz

Computer Systems Engineer

linkedin.com/in/andy · +506 6406 0470 · anjord302@gmail.com

Junior Systems Engineer with experience in software development using C#, .Net, Java and Spring Boot. I stand out for adapting quickly to new environments and agile methodologies, and for my ability to solve complex problems. I have contributed to successful projects working in teams and continuously improving.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Federación Costarricense de Taekwondo (Professional practice)

FullStack Developer

July 2023-December 2023

- Analyzed, designed and developed a web administrator system to manage fights, events, academies and athletes.
- Implemented a secure backend with Java, Spring Boot, JWT and Spring Security.
- I developed an interactive user interface with ReactJS and Vite.
- Managed the database using MySQL.

University Project

Software Developer

January 2023-July 2023

- Designed and developed a mobile application to display ceramic designs and prices.
- Implemented roles and used Java, XML and Firebase for data management.

University Project

Software Developer

January 2022-May 2022

- Designed and developed a web system for the administration of a point of sale in a minimarket.
- Implemented key functionalities such as inventory, sales and customer management.
- I used technologies such as C#, .NET Core, MVC. I developed an interactive user interface with JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript.
- Managed the database using SQL Server.

EDUCATION

Universidad Latina de Costa Rica

Baccalaureate in Computer Systems Engineering.

December 2023

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Technology tools: C# / .NET / Java / Spring boot / SQL Server / MySQL / ReactJS / Git-GitHub / Javascrip
- Passion for learning, Problem solving, Empathetic, Proactive, Adaptable, Responsible, Self-starter, Team player, Emotional intelligence.
- Spanish(native), English B1(in process)